# Siddhi Shukla

Mobile: +11- 9591213356 Email: sidhhishukla54@gmail.com

# **Career Summary**

- ➤ Total 10 years of experience in IT.
- ▶8 years of experience as Data Scientist.
- ➤ Has knowledge and hands-on experience in R, Python, Machine Learning, SQL ➤ Enthusiastic and passionate to learn new technologies.
- >Good written and verbal communication skills.

Technical Skills	
Programming Skills	R, Python, Machine Learning, SQL, PL/SQL
Database	Hive, Teradata, Oracle SQL
ML Algorithms	Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, Time Series, Naïve Bayes, Decision Trees, Random Forest, MBA, Neural Networks, K-Means SVM, NLP, Deep Learning
Utility Tools	Jupyter Notebook, PyCharm, R studio, Spyder, SVN, Bitbucket and SQL Developer
Professional Experience	

#### Company - Legato Healthcare (Feb 2020 - Present)

Role: Data Scientist - Tech Lead Duration:

Feb 2020 - Present

#### **Project Details:**

- 1. Condition Prediction models Leading a team of 8 members to work on 90+ Acute conditions for members. Work closely with client to understand and gather business requirement, design the architect and high level design.
- 2. Kodiak CHP model Developed various clinical models for prediction of diabetes in 6 months, procedural endoscopy.
- 3. SPF care management The changing target definitions made the models in production inconsistent. Developed care management models that improved user experience.
- 4. Stars models Developed Rx models with different custom features that helped in improving model performance.
- 5. POC on Recommendation engine
- 6. DxCG analysis 3rd party vendor supporting variables that were to be rolled out at the end of 2021, analyzed if the variables are significant based on their occurrence rate and correlation matrix. Developed models with some variants that involved different version of these variable to check the impact.

#### Responsibilities:

- 1. Requirement gathering and spec creation.
- 2. Preparation of master driver tables that have member level information.
- 3. Preparation of model driver tables and merge it with table that has 18k+ features for the members.
- 4. Perform feature selection using SHAP values, Random forest or XGBoost feature importance.
- 5. Perform EDA on the dataset.
- 6. Check for class imbalance and apply different techniques like SMOTE.
- 7. Build models and perform in-time and out-of-time validation.
- 8. Check the model performance on basis of AUC, ROC, PPV, Recall.
- 9. Documentation as per RACI checklist.
- 10. Handover to production team.

### Infosys Ltd (Dec 2017 - Jan 2020)

**Role: Technology Analyst** 

**Project Details:** Proposing ideas to build solutions for MS-Dynamics CRM. Building solutions like Customer Churn prediction and Sales forecast using machine learning algorithms with R, Python and Azure ML

### Responsibilities:

- Involved in proposing new idea/solutions.
- Building models for the solutions.
- Preparing SDD and test cases.
- Involved in testing and deployment.
- I have worked as a data scientist, build an ML model to predict the category of template, which is used to extract the data fields.
- Responsible for building Regular expressions to extract different field values.
- Responsible for proactively working on the Analysis, Design and Coding Phases of the METSA project.
- Responsible for creating Solution Design Document.
- Create code deliverable in Python.
- Responsible for Unit Testing.
- Responsible for resolving defects raised during System Testing ad UAT and ensuring smooth delivery of the project.

Company - IBM (Nov 2012 - Nov 2017)

**Role: Application Developer** 

### Responsibilities:

# To predict the most frequent error messages for respective error modules.

• Implemented Naive Bayes to predict the error messages and error modules • Using confusion matrix, ROC and AUC, predicted the most accurate model.

### To predict the invoice amount

Implemented Linear Regression to predict the invoice amount based on the independent variables.

Prior to the roles and responsibilities of data science and ML, I worked as an Oracle eBS techno functional.

### **Qualifications:**

B.Tech in Electronics and Communications from Sobhasaria Engineering college, RTU, Kota 2008-2012

I hereby declare that the information given herewith is correct to my knowledge and belief.

Place: Bangalore (Siddhi Shukla)